Adhish Maheswaran

Toronto, Ontario CA

J 343-961-5800

adhish0001@gmail.com III linkedin.com/in/adhish-maheswaran/ ↑ https://github.com/adhish2001

Cloud/DevOps Engineer with 2+ years of experience in cloud infrastructure automation, DevOps methodologies, and security tooling. Experienced in Terraform, Ansible, and Kubernetes, and most proficient with AWS and VMware vCenter.

Experience

Shared Services Canada — Services partagés Canada · IT-02

Aug 2024 - Present

DevOps Engineer-Multi-Domain Automation Services

Toronto, Ontario

- Created Ansible Playbooks that automate the deployment of VMs and the instance creation of applications, thus replacing manual VM deployments in our vCenter
- Provisioned and optimized application tools in development environments, including Ansible Platform, GitLab, Active Directory, within vCenter, enhancing service reliability and streamlining production updates
- Deployed and configured Backstage, a service portal framework, to create a front-end interface for non-technical skilled clients to leverage our teams' ansible playbooks

Solace · Co-op

May 2023 - Aug 2023

Software Developer-Cloud-Infra

Ottawa, Ontario

- · Led security improvements by integrating static IAC tools such as tfsec and checkov scans across Terraform Modules, through Github Action integration
- Created and added Open Policy Agent (OPA) policies to Atlantis Terraform Pull Request automation, policy enforcement, delivering personalized security improvements to our CI/CD
- Documented and resolved 10+ security warnings and vulnerabilities detected by the implemented static scan tools

Solace · Co-op

May 2022 - Aug 2022

Software Developer-Cloud-Infra

Ottawa, Ontario

- Authored Terraform modules to replace AWS CloudFormation, conducted rigorous testing, and supported a seamless migration from AWS
- Leveraged Kubernetes for implementing blue-green deployments of HashiCorp Vault (a secret management tool), enabling zero-downtime service transitions
- Developed and executed scripts using Vault APIs and Python to conduct Infrastructure Reliability Testing, making sure all secrets and paths were unaffected by migration

Shared Services Canada — Services partagés Canada · Co-op

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Junior Software Dev

Ottawa, Ontario

- Designed and implemented Ansible playbooks to automate the configuration of remote servers, created proof-of-concept (POC) solutions, and demonstrated web application deployment processes
- Streamlined the deployment of remote servers using vRealize Automation, reducing manual intervention

Canadian Food Inspection Agency · Co-op

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

Junior Software Dev

 $Ottawa,\ Ontario$

- Documented the setup, configurations, and custom scripts or extensions utilized in Azure Pipelines to ensure clarity and reproducibility
- Designed and configured pipelines to automate testing, ensuring reliable and efficient software delivery processes.

Education

University of Ottawa

Sep 2019 – May 2024

Bachelor of Applied Science Software Engineering (Engineering Management and Entrepreneurship)

Ottawa, Ontario

Certificates/Screenings

HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003) Understanding basic concepts, skills, and use-cases of Terraform AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner fundamental understanding of IT services and their uses in the AWS Cloud Machine Learning Skills Challenge August 2023 Microsoft Azure - Applying AI models to pipelines Basic Reliability Screening Govt of Canada Security Clearance

Volunteer Experience

Fitshare, Full-Stack Developer | MERN Stack

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

- Developed a comprehensive web application tailored to the needs of personal trainers, leveraging the MERN stack for seamless performance
- Built responsive and visually appealing front-end interfaces using TypeScript and Tailwind CSS, ensuring optimal user experience across devices
- Implemented automated reliability testing for front-end components with Selenium, enhancing overall application stability

Software For Love, Full-Stack Developer

Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

- Engineered high-performance websites using Gatsby, a React-based framework, achieving faster loading times and improved user interaction
- Collaborated on creating detailed design mock-ups in Figma, translating client requirements into intuitive, visually appealing web interfaces

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, YAML, Shell Scripting

Infrastructure as Code (IaC): Terraform, Ansible, AWS CloudFormation

Cloud Platforms: AWS, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), VMware vSphere/vCenter

Containerization and Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes

Version Control and CI/CD: GitHub, GitLab, Atlantis, Jenkins, Azure Pipelines Security Tools: HashiCorp Vault, Checkov, TFSec, Open Policy Agent (OPA) Frontend Frameworks and Libraries: React.js, Gatsby, Tailwind CSS

Developer Tools: VS Code, Jira, Figma, Selenium